Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Labor Movement Serials WAG.345
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: International Labor Organizations, 1894-2010; 18.7 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 15 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 26 flat boxes
  - Massenstreik Partei und Gewerkschaften: Vulkan-Verlag, Leipzig, Germany, 1910; cuid9613 (Box 139, Folder 28)
  - IRRU Newsletter: Warwick Printing Co. Ltd./Industrial Relations Research Unit, University of Warwick, Warwick, England/Coventry, England, 1990, 1992; cuid9614 (Box 139, Folder 29)
  - WAMT Newsletter: Woman and Manual Trades, London, England, 1989-1991; cuid9615 (Box 139, Folder 30)
  - Worker Today: Worker Today, Stockholm, Sweden, 1991; cuid9616 (Box 139, Folder 31)
  - Future of British Agriculture: Workers Educational Association, London, England, circa 1970s; cuid9617 (Box 139, Folder 32)
  - Studies for Trade Unionists: Workers' Educational Association, London, England, 1982-1988; cuid9618 (Box 139, Folder 35)
  - Summer Highway: Workers' Educational Association, London, England, 1950; cuid9619 (Box 139, Folder 36)
  - Trade Union Studies Journal: Workers' Educational Association, London, England, 1981-1985, 1988, 1990; cuid9620 (Box 139, Folder 37)
  - WHIN: Workers Health International, Sheffield, England, 1994-1999; cuid9621 (Box 139, Folder 33-34)
  - "Kav La'oved" - Workers' Hotline for the Protection of Workers' Rights: Workers' Hotline, Tel-Aviv, Israel, 1993-1995; cuid9622 (Box 139, Folder 38)
  - Law and Order on the Shop Floor?: Workshop Books, Coventry, England, circa 1970s; cuid9623 (Box 139, Folder 39)
  - Working Women Shape Their Future: 2nd International Conference on the Problems of Working Women: World Federation of Trade Unions/PRACE, Prague, Czechoslovakia, 1964 (Box 189, Folder 15)
  - Unity Solidarity: World Trade Union Movement, London, England, 1954; cuid9624 (Box 139, Folder 40)
  - Information Bulletin: World Union of the United Workers' Party (MAPAM), Tel Aviv, Israel, 1965 (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Compte Rendu: Xe Congres International des Travailleurs de l'Industrie du Textile, Paris, France, 1921; cuid9625 (Box 139, Folder 41)
  - Korean Worker: Newsletter of the Yong Dong Po Urban Industrial Mission: Yong Dong Po Urban Industrial Mission, Seoul, South Korea, 1997; cuid9626 (Box 139, Folder 42)
  - Arbeit und Leben: Dusseldorf, Germany, 1965; cuid9627 (Box 139, Folder 43)
  - Arbeitsrechts-Gratis: Zeitschrift für Arbeitsrecht, Sozialversicherung und Soziale Verwaltung, 1928 (Box 180, Folder 3)
  - Betriebsräte-Beitſchrift für die Funktionäre der Metallinduſtrie: Stuttgart, Germany, 1930; cuid9628 (Box 139, Folder 44)
  - Companhia de Diamantes de Angola (DIAMANG): Lisboa, Portugal, 1959 (Box 180, Folder 7)
  - Correspondences Internationales: Suresnes, France, 1998 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Der Kampf fur die einheit der Weltgewerkschafts-bewegung: Berlin, Germany, 1925; cuid9629 (Box 123, Folder 107)
  - INDECOSA: Montreuil, France, 1996; cuid9630 (Box 139, Folder 45)
  - International Federation of Building Workers: Berlin, Germany, 1930-1932; cuid9631 (Box 139, Folder 46)
  - International Labor Press of America: Newark, NJ, 1953; cuid9632 (Box 139, Folder 47)
  - Labour Record and Review: London, England, 1906; cuid9633 (Box 123, Folder 108)
  - Labour Review: Melbourne, Australia, circa 1970s; cuid9634 (Box 140, Folder 2)
  - PrintWorker: London, England, circa 1970s; cuid9635 (Box 123, Folder 105)
  - SAC Kontakt: Stockholm, Sweden, 1990 (Box 183, Folder 20)
  - Stockholms LS-Meddelande: Stockholm, Sweden, 1996-1999; cuid9636 (Box 140, Folder 5)
  - Travail & Securite, 1995-1996; cuid9637 (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - Tronquistas Adelante, 2002; cuid9638 (Box 123, Folder 106)
  - Zur Krise der Arbeiterbewegung, 1946; cuid9639 (Box 140, Folder 9)
- Series V: Labor Research, 1915-2008; 7.1 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 7 manuscript boxes, and 3 flat boxes
  This series collects a variety of serials and publications largely issued by institutions specializing in labor research and history. These include newsletters and catalogs produced by the George Meany Center for Labor Studies and the School of Industrial and Labor Relations, as well as material published by smaller organizations like the American Labor Museum, Ozarks' Labor Union Archive, and New England Free Press. Other titles include independently produced reports on topics including collective bargaining, outsourcing in manufacturing, and general strikes in France; catalogues rounding up labor titles distributed by Greenwood Press and Charles H. Kerr & Co; and a journal of new workplace technology, Black Chip.
  - 100th Anniversary Journal - Haymarket - May Day - The Struggle for the Eight Hour Day: 100th Anniversary Committee, New York, NY, 1986; cuid9640 (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - But What About the Workers?: Advocators, Detroit, MI, 1973; cuid9641 (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report of the American Labor Education Service, Inc.: American Labor Education Service, New York, NY, 1954; cuid9642 (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - American Labor Museum Newsletter: American Labor Museum, Haledon, NJ, 1983, 1987, 1989, 1990, 1995, 1996, 1998, 2000, 2001, 2004, 2005; cuid9643 (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Slice of the Earth: American Labor Museum, Haledon, NJ, 1983; cuid9644 (Box 161, Folder 5)
  - Fifteenth Annual Sol Stetin Awards Dinner Honoring Pete Seeger and John Tesaro: American Labor Museum Botto House National Landmark, Haledon, NJ, 1997; cuid9645 (Box 161, Folder 6)
  - ASHP News: American Social History Project, New York, NY, 1996; cuid9646 (Box 161, Folder 7)
  - Institute for Labor Studies Survey: Appalachian Center West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV, 1970; cuid9647 (Box 172, Folder 52)
  - Beaver Valley Labor History Journal: Beaver Valley Labor History Society, Alquippa, PA, 1979-1980; cuid9648 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Canadian Mining Review: Canadian Mining Review, Toronto, Canada, 1947; cuid9649 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - American Labor: ComCor, Inc., 1968; cuid9650 (Box 162, Folder 12)
  - ILR Labor Advance: Cornell University ILR School, New York, NY, 2008; cuid9651 (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - The Italian Labor Movement: Cornell University Press, Ithaca, New York, 1957; cuid9652 (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Labor Movement in the United States: Department of Public Instruction, Harrisburg, PA, 1963; cuid9653 (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - Union Town - A Labor History Guide to Detroit: Detroit Labor History Tour Project, Detroit, MI, circa 1980; cuid9654 (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Eight-Hour Day Bulletin ('Eight-Huor Day Bulletin'): Eight-Hour Workday Conference, Paterson, NJ, 1919; cuid9655 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - EBRI News: Employee Benefit Research Institute, Washington, DC, 1989; cuid9656 (Box 161, Folder 12)
  - Catalogue: George Meany Center for Labor Studies, 1976-1995; cuid9657 (Box 161, Folder 13-14)
  - Clearinghouse Newsbrief: George Meany Center for Labor Studies, 1995; cuid9658 (Box 161, Folder 16)
  - Laborite: George Meany Center for Labor Studies, Silver Spring, MD, 1975, 1979, 1980-1982; cuid9659 (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - Labor's Heritage: George Meany Center for Labor Studies, 1991; cuid9660 (Box 161, Folder 15)
  - Newsletter: George Meany Memorial Archives, 1995; cuid9661 (Box 161, Folder 17)
  - New Books in History: Greenwood Press, Westport, CT, 1980; cuid9662 (Box 161, Folder 18)
  - Illinois Labor History Society Reporter: Illinois Labor History Society, Chicago, IL, 1995, 1998, 1999, 2001; cuid9663 (Box 161, Folder 19)
  - New Books from Charles H. Kerr: Illinois Labor History Society, Chicago, IL, 1999; cuid9664 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Dialogues: Industrial Relations Research Association, Madison, WI, 1993; cuid9665 (Box 161, Folder 20)
  - Power in Industrial Relations - Its Use and Abuse: Industrial Relations Research Association, St. Louis, MO, 1958; cuid9666 (Box 161, Folder 22)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association Series Newsletter: Industrial Relations Research Association (IRRA), Madison, WI, 1977, 1989, 1993, 1995, 1996, 2003, 2004; cuid9667 (Box 161, Folder 21)
  - Research Review: Industrial Relations Research Unit at University of Warwick (IRRU), Coventry, England, 1992; cuid9668 (Box 161, Folder 28)
  - Dataline: Institute for the Study of Labor and Economic Crisis, San Francisco, CA, 1984; cuid9669 (Box 161, Folder 23)
  - Bibliographic Contributions No. 4 - The Worker in American Fiction: Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, Champaign, IL, 1954; cuid9670 (Box 161, Folder 24)
  - Labor Management Relations: A List of Selected Readings for High Schools: Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations and the College of Education, University of Illinois, Urbana, Urbana, IL, 1956; cuid9671 (Box 161, Folder 25)
  - The Louisiana Sugar Cane Plantation Workers vs. The Sugar Corporations, US Department of Agriculture, et al.: An Account of human relations on Corporation-owned Sugar Cane Plantations in Louisiana under the Operation of the US Sugar Program 1937-1953: Inter-American Educational Association, Inc., Washington, DC, 1954; cuid9672 (Box 161, Folder 26)
  - International Labour Office reports: International Labour Office, Geneva, Switzerland, 1962-1964; cuid9673 (Box 161, Folder 27)
  - Studies in Labor History: John L Noyce, Sussex, UK, 1976; cuid9674 (Box 161, Folder 29)
  - Some Problems of Work in Right-led Unions by John Swift: John Swift/TU-555, 1952; cuid9675 (Box 162, Folder 14)
  - Man Behind the Scenes - Julius C. C. Edelstein: La Guardia and Wagner Archives, circa 2002; cuid9676 (Box 161, Folder 30)
  - Art Works: Labor Heritage Foundation, Washington, DC, 1992 (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - Unions and Free Trade: Solidarity vs. Competition by Kim Moody & Mary McGinn: Labor Notes, Detroit, MI, 1992; cuid9677 (Box 161, Folder 31)
  - Future of Labor: Labor Research Association, 1992; cuid9678 (Box 161, Folder 32)
  - Report #1: Labor Study Project, Yeadon, PA, 1980; cuid9679 (Box 172, Folder 59)
  - Labour Archives Bulletin: Labour Archives Committee of the Association of Canadian Archivists, Ottawa, Canada, 1987 (Box 198, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Steel: The Betrayal of America: Midwest Center for Labor Research, circa 1983; cuid9680 (Box 161, Folder 32)
  - Studies in Personnel Policy: National Industrial Conference Board, Inc., New York, NY, 1955; cuid9681 (Box 161, Folder 33)
  - Unemployment - The Wolf at the Door - by Art Shields: New Century Publishers, New York, NY, 1958; cuid9682 (Box 172, Folder 72)
  - A Guide to Working Class History: New England Free Press/New Hogtown Press, Somerville, MA/Toronto, Canada, circa 1970s; cuid9683 (Box 161, Folder 34)
  - Lichtenstein's Fictions: Meany, Reuther and the 1964 Civil Rights Act by Herbert Hill: New Politics, 1998; cuid9684 (Box 161, Folder 35)
  - Industrial and Labor Relations Report: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1978; cuid9685 (Box 162, Folder 13)
  - Abstracts and Annotations...: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 1954; cuid9686 (Box 162, Folder 19)
  - Extension Bulletin: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 1950; cuid9687 (Box 162, Folder 15)
  - Industrial Mobility of Labor as a Probability Process: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Ithaca, NY, 1955 (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - Key Issues Series: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Ithaca, NY, 1975 (Box 184, Folder 3)
  - Public Employee Relations Report: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Ithaca, NY, 1989 (Box 184, Folder 8)
  - Bulletin: New York State School of Industrial & Labor Relations at Cornell, Ithaca, NY, 1955 (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - Industrial and Labor Relations Review: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 1964 (Box 187, Folder 2)
  - Legacy of the Workers Party, 1940-1949: New York University Libraries, New York, NY, 1985; cuid9688 (Box 161, Folder 36)
  - Newsletter: Ozarks' Labor Union Archive, Southwest Missouri State University, Springfield, MO, 1985; cuid9689 (Box 161, Folder 37)
  - Pacific Northwest Labor History Association: Pacific Northwest Labor History Association, Seattle, WA, 1992 (Box 184, Folder 7)
  - Songs for Workers of Washington: Pacific Northwest Labor History Association, Seattle, WA, 1989; cuid9690 (Box 161, Folder 38)
  - A Chapter in Labor History: Pennsylvania Joint Board, Allentown, PA, 1958; cuid9691 (Box 161, Folder 39)
  - Printing Management: Penton Publishing co, Cleveland, OH, 1970; cuid9692 (Box 161, Folder 40)
  - The Great Sit-Down Strike Against G.M. - How Industrial Unionism Was Won: Radical Education Project, Ann Arbor, MI, circa 1970s; cuid9693 (Box 161, Folder 41)
  - American Federation of Labor Records: Research Collections in Labor Studies, Frederick, MD, 1986; cuid9694 (Box 161, Folder 42)
  - Black Chip: Richard Alexander, 1988; cuid9695 (Box 161, Folder 43)
  - Press release on 'New Yorkers at Work' oral history series: Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives of the Tamiment Institute Library, New York, NY, 1981; cuid9696 (Box 161, Folder 44)
  - Labor Archives & Research Center pamphlet: San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA, circa 1990s; cuid9697 (Box 161, Folder 45)
  - Institute of Collective Bargaining - Working Paper Series: School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Ithaca, NY, 1992; cuid9698 (Box 161, Folder 46)
  - ILR Alumni Bulletin: School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Ithaca, NY, 1967 (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - ILR Press: School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 1994; cuid9699 (Box 161, Folder 47)
  - Society for the study of Labour History Bulletin: Society for the study of Labour History, 1960-1969, 1987-1989; cuid9700 (Box 162, Folder 1-4)
  - General Strike France 1968: A Factory-by-Factory Account: Sojourner Truth Organization, Chicago, IL, circa 1970s; cuid9701 (Box 161, Folder 48)
  - Columns: State Historical Society of Wisconsin, Madison, WI, 1997 (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Studies in Employment and Unemployment: The W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research, Kalamazoo, MI, 1965 (Box 184, Folder 10-11)
  - 36 Years - Drawings: The Worker, 1960; cuid9702 (Box 172, Folder 51)
  - Let's Have the Truth: Thompson, Cleveland, OH, 1944; cuid9703 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Labor Education News: UCLA Center for Labor Research & Education, Los Angeles, CA, 1994 (Box 185, Folder 7)
  - International Runaway Shop: Why US Companies Are Moving Their Plants Abroad: United Front Press, San Francisco, CA, 1972; cuid9704 (Box 161, Folder 49)
  - Soldiers and Strikers: Counterinsurgency on the Labor Front 1877-1970: United Front Press, San Francisco, CA, 1974 (Box 184, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin No. 1026 - Elements of Soviet Labor Law: United States Department of Labor, 1951; cuid9705 (Box 161, Folder 50)
  - Industrial Relations Law Journal: University of California Berkeley, Berkeley, CA, 1977 (Box 198, Folder 9)
  - Labor Research Center News and Notes: University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI, 1997, 2006; cuid9706 (Box 161, Folder 51)
  - Letters to Judd: An American Workingman: Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, CA, 1932; cuid9707 (Box 161, Folder 52)
  - Labor Press Service: US Department of Labor, Washington, DC, 1956; cuid9708 (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - Phillips-Van Heusen Campaign Update: US/Guatemala Labor Education Project, Chicago, IL, 1992; cuid9709 (Box 162, Folder 6)
  - US/Labor Education in the Americas Project: US/Labor Education in the Americas Project (US/LEAP), Chicago, IL, 2004; cuid9710 (Box 162, Folder 7)
  - Wisconsin Labor History News: Wisconsin Labor History Society, Milwaukee, WI, 1990; cuid9711 (Box 162, Folder 8)
  - Progress Report: Work in America Institute, Inc., 1988; cuid9712 (Box 162, Folder 9)
  - Southern Cotton Mills and Labor: Workers Library Publishers, 1929; cuid9713 (Box 162, Folder 10)
  - Why We March for Unemployment Insurance!: Workers Library Publishers, 1932; cuid9714 (Box 162, Folder 11)
  - Neponset Review, 1915; cuid9715 (Box 83, Folder 7)